[{
    "question": "In the context of the OSI Model, which layers are primarily concerned with the establishment of a TCP / IP connection ?",
    "dom": "network",
    "answer": "a",
    "a": "Transport and Network",
    "b": "Session and Network",
    "c": "Application and Presentation",
    "d": "Network Layer Only",
    "feedback": "A, The Network layer uses IP to route data, while the Transport layer uses TCP to ensure delivery. The Physical and Data-link layers are concerned with the physical hardware or network interface device. The Session, Application, and Presentation layers are used for web application functionality."
}, {
    "question": "Considering that you work for a financial institution that is heavily regulated. Which technique would be BEST for prioritising control implementation?",
    "dom": "grc",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "Third party penetration test / red team to understand control deficiencies and gaps.",
    "b": "Perform a gap analysis against a regulatory standard such as CPS 234.",
    "c": "Cost / Benefit analysis of controls that target risk areas outside of appetite.",
    "d": "Study sector peers and their approach to control implementation.",
    "feedback": "C, Cost / Benefit analysis allows to select controls within financial means that target key risk areas. External penetration tests will not provide adequate coverage of internal issues and are inefficient to audit with. Consulting a regulatory standard will help improve overall posture, but provides limited guidance to prioritise or contextualise control selection for your organisation. Sector peers, while helpful, may have entirely different people, processes, and products which makes them difficult to compare with. "
},
{
    "question": "A business is having a production outage for their online sales portal. The business owner believes the Web Application Firewall is the cause of the outage. What is the MOST TIMELY approach to confirm that the WAF is the cause?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "d",
    "a": "Enter the WAF console and look at historical traffic records and see if there is a noticeable change in traffic from the outage time.",
    "b": "Enter the WAF console and look at events from the outage period for high Deny rates.",
    "c": "Check with major vendors whether there is a known production outage affecting their systems.",
    "d": "Talk to the engineering managers about any scheduled changes to the production system.",
    "feedback": "D, Engineering managers will know of scheduled changes, and if a change was made without modifying rules for the WAF, it is likely the WAF can cause outages. Traffic Analysis can identify a change in the frequency of packets sent, but will not clearly demonstrate that the WAF resulted in this change. High Deny Rates can indicate that the WAF is blocking new traffic, but it will require investigation to understand why. Major Vendor outages can cause production outages, but vendors will take time to respond to queries. "
},
{
    "question": "A Web Application Firewall needs a rule update. What approach would BEST balance security and system availability?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "Continuously update rulesets as part of the deployment process, to always have the latest security rulepacks available",
    "b": "Update rulesets in a staging environment exclusively and run manual tests before migrating to production to minimise unexpected availability concerns.",
    "c": "Update rules, enforce in ALERT Only, and monitor. Tweak rules as needed and change to DENY.",
    "d": "Update rules, enforce in ALERT Only, and run manual tests in the staging environment. Then promote the rules to production in ALERT Only.",
    "feedback": "C, Having ALERT Only in production will allow for adequate testing of the rule upgrades, tweaking to minimise disruption, and then swapping to DENY will improve security outcomes.Continuously updating rulepacks may cause availability issues from new security rules. Running manual tests in a staging environment will not provide enough coverage as a production test. Keeping rules in ALERT Only in production will maximise availability, but unless people are monitoring the ALERTs and they are tweaked to reduce false positives, the security provided by the WAF is minimal."
},
{
    "question": "Consider you work for a medical practice based in the US, which of these regulatory standards are the MOST appropriate to implement?",
    "dom": "grc",
    "answer": "a",
    "a": "HIPPA",
    "b": "FIPS182",
    "c": "ISO27001",
    "d": "COPPA",
    "feedback": "A, HIPPA specifically relates to protecting healthcare data appropriately, a key concern for a healthcare company. Encryption, Organisational Risk Frameworks, and Child Protection regulation are not as important as HIPPA in this context."
},
{
    "question": "You have noticed that one of your servers has been making DNS queries to an unknown DNS provider. The queries appear to match a pattern similar to 2313983912fa93f920a092faac.dreidaasd.ru, and are being sent in groups of 400 requests on an hourly basis. What is the MOST likely reason ?",
    "dom": "network",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "IT has misconfigured a DNS server and garbage queries are being sent to the void.",
    "b": "dreidaasd.ru is a well-known russian DNS provider and this traffic is legitimate.",
    "c": "This is an example of DNS exfiltration by using the subdomain to transmit encoded data.",
    "d": "This is an example of beaconing, by using these DNS requests to ping a C&C server for instructions.",
    "feedback": "C, Encoded Data is being transmitted via a subdomain, as a means to bypass many types of filters, detection systems, and more. A misconfigured DNS server is unlikely to send data to a potentially malicious domain and on such a regular schedule. dreidaasd.ru is not a DNS provider. This is not beaconing due to the intense burts of traffic. Beaconing is more likely to be covert and infrequent."
},
{
    "question": "Take this command: tshark -i wlan0 -Y 'http.request.method == POST and tcp contains password' | grep password. What is happening here?",
    "dom": "network",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "Tshark is listening for all POST requests to the wlan0 domain that have a password.",
    "b": "Tshark is capturing all traffic on the wlan0 interface that have passwords in it.",
    "c": "Tshark is listening for POST requests on the wlan0 interface that contain the word password in it, and then using grep to acquire the exact line that the password is displayed. ",
    "d": "Tshark is listening for all network traffic that contains the word password. All traffic is then sent to grep to quickly gather passwords.",
    "feedback": "C, Tshark is listening for POST requests that have password data in the POST Data, and then grep is filtering the request for that line specifically. wlan0 is an interface not a domain. Tshark is not capturing traffic with this command, and also not capturing ALL traffic. Tshark is only listening for POST requests, not other network traffic."
},
{
    "question": "Which of the statements below is true of SSL and TLS? ",
    "dom": "network",
    "answer": "d",
    "a": "SSL is an old implementation of TLS, TLS has no weaknesses.",
    "b": "TLS is a rebrand of SSL to move away from branding concerns.",
    "c": "SSL is used primarily to secure websockets, whereas TLS encrypts the Transport layer",
    "d": "TLS is a new protocol created to address the shortcomings of SSL.",
    "feedback": "D, TLS is a new protocol to succeed and improve upon SSL. TLS and SSL are separate protocols, not a new implementation. TLS may have weaknesses. TLS is a new protocol, not a rebrand. SSL may be used to encrypt websockets but is not primarily used for this. TLS should be used instead for websockets."
},
{
    "question": "The effectiveness of a Phishing Simulation campaign can be BEST measured by.",
    "dom": "grc",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "The quantity of staff clicking on phishing simulation links over time.",
    "b": "The quantity of staff within a demographic clicking on a phishing simulation link over time.",
    "c": "The quantity of staff reporting a phishing simulation email over time.",
    "d": "The quantity of staff within a demographic trained to report a phishing simulation link.",
    "feedback": "c, Better reporting helps demonstrate an improvement in incident identification and response time. Quantity of people clicking a phishing email shows who or what demographic need training, but there are diminishing returns for further investment in education and awareness programs. Measuring who has been trained to report a phishing email, is not as effective as actual reports."
},
{
    "question": "Consider the origin https://www.colecornford.com/flashcards. Which of the following explanations is correct in regards to the Same-Origin Policy.",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "D",
    "a": "http://www.colecornford.com > The host is different, so this would fail.",
    "b": "https://cole:corn@www.colecornford.com/dir3 > URL Authentication is considered fine when all elements of the policy (Scheme, Host, and Path) are the same.",
    "c": "https://flashcards.colecornford.com > The subdomain is considered fine in regards to the same origin, as the host only considers the TLD.",
    "d": "wss://www.colecornford.com > The scheme is websockets, but the origin contains a different scheme, this would fail according to the Same-Origin Policy.",
    "feedback": "D, this answer is correct despite WSS being used, the rest have issues with their explanations. A, the Scheme is different not the host. B, ignoring the URL authentication, the explanation incorrectly states that Scheme / Host / Path comprise an origin, when it should be Scheme / Host / Port instead. C, subdomains are considered different hosts."
},
{
    "question": "Which of these scenarios for a CORS policy is correct ?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "a",
    "a": "A pre-flight request of Access-Control-Request-Method: POST is submitted to the web-server. The server replies with an Access-Control-Allow-Origin: https://www.colecornford.com and Access-Control-Allow-Methods: POST, GET, OPTIONS. The Client then submits a request adhering to the allowed methods. ",
    "b": "A get request for https://www.colecornford.com is submitted. The web server responds with an Access-Control-Allow-Origin: * request. This allows resources to be used from colecornford on any origin and turns off the Same-Origin Policy for subsequent requests. ",
    "c": "An XMLHttpRequest() is submitted to https://www.colecornford.com via inline JavaScript to request w/ an Authentication Cookie set with options SameSite=Strict and HTTPOnly. The server responds with Access-Control-Allow-Credentials: True. The cookie is used to authenticate the CORS request.",
    "d": "A credentialed request is submitted to https://www.colecornford.com. The web server responds with Access-Control-Allow-Origin: * . The calling domain can then use data from colecornford.com cross-origin.",
    "feedback": "A, A is a textbook example of a CORS pre-flight check and subsequent request. CORS does not turn off Same-Origin Policy for all subsequent requests, there is an Access-Control-Max-Age header and failing that a browser default. The cookie attributes prevent the cookie from being interacted with both cross-origin AND using javascript. Credentialled requests cannot use a wildcard ACAO."
},
{
    "question": "Which is the most effective HSTS header for testing initial impact ?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "Strict-Transport-Security: max-age=31536000; includeSubDomains; preload",
    "b": "Strict-Transport-Security: max-age=600; includeSubDomains; preload",
    "c": "Strict-Transport-Security: max-age=600; ",
    "d": "Strict-Transport-Security: max-age=600; includeSubDomains",
    "feedback": "C, Testing impact with a 10 minute max-age will cause limited damage to clients. A is the most secure, but submitting to a browser preload list is a difficult process to reverse. B, websites will not be preloaded without a max-age of at least a year. D, is effective for testing impact across subdomains, but it is better to start with the main domain initially."
},
{
    "question": "What does HSTS protect against ?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "d",
    "a": "HSTS prevents Cross-Site Scripting Attacks by reducing the opportunity for JavaScript to be injected via a Person in the Middle.",
    "b": "HSTS supplements TLS by ensuring that a web browser has a minimum level of cryptographic protocols available for establishing a secure connection.",
    "c": "HSTS prevents Person in the Middle attacks by upgrading all HTTP requests to HTTPS requests after the initial connection to a website.",
    "d": "HSTS prevents Person in the Middle attacks by initially checking a preload list on the client side and upgrading HTTP requests to HTTPS prior to request submission.",
    "feedback": "D, HSTS prevents SSL-strip and other PITM by checking the preload list and changing protocols prior to any connection attempt. HSTS may prevent XSS, but that is not its primary purpose. HSTS does not enforce cryptographic protocol negotiation. HSTS does not protect against the initial connection to a web-site if the HSTS directive is not stored in the browser preload list, or the site has not been visited after the max-age had expired."
},
{
    "question": "What does the Secure cookie attribute do?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "a",
    "a": "Prevents submission of the cookie with all web-requests to insecure origins.",
    "b": "Prevents reading of the cookie data from JavaScript.",
    "c": "Prevents the cookie from being submitted cross-origin.",
    "d": "Encrypts the cookie data in the browser storage.",
    "feedback": "a, Secure prevents submission over insecure channels. HTTPOnly prevents JS access. SameSite, CORS, and SOP protect from cross-domain leakage. It does not encrypt the cookie."
},
{
    "question": "Which of these is NOT an XSS attempt ?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "d",
    "a": "<img src=x onerror=&#0000106&#0000097&#0000118&#0000097&#0000115&#0000099&#0000114&#0000105&#0000112&#0000116&#0000058&#0000097&#0000108&#0000101&#0000114&#0000116&#0000040&#0000039&#0000088&#0000083&#0000083&#0000039&#0000041>",
    "b": "<IMG SRC=jav&#x09;ascript:abc.de/x.j;>",
    "c": "<a aa aaa aaaa aaaaa aaaaaa aaaaaaa aaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaa aaaaaaaaaa href=j&#97v&#97script:&#97lert(1)>ClickMe",
    "d": "password=exec master..xp_dirtree '//YOUR-SUBDOMAIN-HERE.burpcollaborator.net/a'",
    "feedback": "D, exec master is attempting a DNS lookup for SQLi, the remainder are obfuscated XSS payloads. "
},
{
    "question": "Which of these is the BEST reason to NOT use input validation as the primary reason to mitigate XSS ?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "a",
    "a": "The web application you are building has a large number of business scenarios where free-text is required, creating gaps where input validation is counter-productive to business objectives.",
    "b": "The organisation risk-accepted the consequence of XSS affecting their business systems.",
    "c": "The choice of technology frameworks safeguards against the introduction of an XSS vulnerability via templating and automated output encoding.",
    "d": "The Content-Security Policy that has been set only allows code from our primary domain, and from nowhere else, mitigating the risk of external javascript being included.",
    "feedback": "A, Aligning security controls to business objectives is critical to the success of a security program. Risk-acceptance does not mean you should not try to mitigate where possible. Technology frameworks may reduce the opportunity for an exploit to work, but out-of-band XSS is still possible and preventable using IV. A CSP may mitigate third party JS, but reflected and stored JS are still an issue from the primary domain as we have not stated nonce-validation OR wheter unsafe-inline is on."
},
{
    "question": "I entered the commands cd, cd blog, cd images, cd ~/git. I now want to go back to my images folder, what is the MOST effective method ?",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "b",
    "a": "cd ~/blog/images",
    "b": "cd -",
    "c": "cd ~, cd blog, cd images",
    "d": "cd .., pwd, ls, cd blog, cd images",
    "feedback": "B, all answers will take you to that directory, but the hyphen option will take you to the previous working directory without navigating the filesystem directly. navigating to ~/blog/images is more time consuming. typing multiple commands is time consuming. D, while inefficient, represents what a lot of analysts will use."
},
{
    "question": "Considering usability and security, which of these is the BEST password policy ?",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "d",
    "a": "14char Min, Full Complexity Reqs, Rotate Monthly, No re-use",
    "b": "Ban common passwords, no complexity reqs, 8 char minimum, No rotation, password per-system.",
    "c": "Ban common passwords, 14 char Min, Full Complexity Reqs, Rotate Monthly, No re-use",
    "d": "SSO Portal, Ban common passwords, no complexity reqs, 8 char min, yearly rotation",
    "feedback": "D, requires remembering one strong password for access to all systems. Having high password length/complexity requirements results in bad usability AND incentivises weak password selection (repeating words, choosing patterns, choosing 1! at end of passwords). Password Rotation is meant to mitigate cracking attempts, but leads to password variations rather than new passwords. Banning common passwords is a very strong control. Having many passwords leads to poor usability (without a password manager) and increased resets + opportunities to introduce weak passwords."
},
{
    "question": "Which of these devices meets this requirement 'Forward or drop traffic based on an IP address'",
    "dom": "network",
    "answer": "d",
    "a": "Hub",
    "b": "Switch",
    "c": "Bridge",
    "d": "Router",
    "feedback": "Routers forward or drop traffic to IP addresses. The other three are used internally to send data internally generally."
},
{
    "question": "The 'HELO' command is part of which protocol ?",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "DNS",
    "b": "HTTPS",
    "c": "SMTP",
    "d": "SSH",
    "feedback": "C, HELO is part of an SMTP connection to identify itself."
},
{
    "question": "What would the following command achieve: 'ssh-keygen -f ~/cole-key-ecdsa -t ecdsa -b 521'",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "b",
    "a": "Immediate generation with no further input of an SSH key using system defaults.",
    "b": "Generation of an SSH public/private key pair using the Digital Signature Algorithm w. a keylength of 521 bits.",
    "c": "Starting an SSH connection using the SSH-Keygen command to the cole-key-ecdsa server on port 521.",
    "d": "This command is invalid and will error due to missing required parameters.",
    "feedback": "B, This command has been given the file location, the algorithm, and the size options, so it will generate a key using those. If any mandatory options are unspecified, the command will ask you for input. ssh-keygen does not initiate a connection (normally). This command is valid."
},
{
    "question": "You are working at a small government institution. Your external auditor has identified non-compliance with a government security standard. As the security manager, what would be your FIRST action?",
    "dom": "grc",
    "answer": "b",
    "a": "Immediately implement the controls identified in the audit.",
    "b": "Perform a risk assessment of the areas the controls are missing from, and priotise work there.",
    "c": "Build a business case to implement all of the controls as part of the next FY.",
    "d": "Ask ASD to fix your control gaps for you.",
    "feedback": "B, prioritising security-work is important for under-resourced government departments. Implementing controls without consultation or prioritisation may have adverse affects elsewhere in the business and the controls may be unnecessary. A business case is useful to obtain funding, but it should be built using input from a risk assessment. ASD is not here to fix your control gaps."
},
{
    "question": "What does Address Resolution Protocol do?",
    "dom": "network",
    "answer": "a",
    "a": "A host on a LAN uses ARP to determine the MAC address of another host on the same LAN.",
    "b": "A host on a LAN uses ARP to determine the IP address of another host on the same LAN.",
    "c": "A default gateway on a LAN uses ARP to determine the IP address of another router external to its LAN.",
    "d": "ARP is used to authenticate all MAC addresses on a LAN and blocklist unknown ones.",
    "feedback": "A, ARP is used to identify MAC addresses for devices on a LAN. Routers use IP to distribute packets. NACL's and higher level protocols are used for authentication. ARP is used for an internal network. An ARP packet looks like 'Who has 172.20.42.1? tell 172.20.42.2'"
},
{
    "question": "Why was DNS initially invented ?",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "b",
    "a": "Because we were running out of IP Addresses to assign.",
    "b": "For usability by humans.",
    "c": "For faster processing by computers and routers.",
    "d": "To allow hosts to change IP addresses easily.",
    "feedback": "B, for usability by humans. DNS maps an IP address to a Domain Name. This allows humans to remember something like https://www.colecornford.com, but it is not easy to remember an exact IP address. The other options are wrong."
},
{
    "question": "For a TCP connection, which of the following flags is INVALID ?",
    "dom": "NILK",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "ACK",
    "b": "SYN",
    "c": "NOOP",
    "d": "FIN",
    "feedback": "C, NOOP is a TCP Option, not a Flag. URG, ACK, PSH, RST, SYN, and FIN are all the valid flags for a TCP connection. "
},
{
    "question": "In which of the following scenarios would UDP NOT be the optimal choice over using TCP ?",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "b",
    "a": "For playing League of Legends",
    "b": "An online shopping website",
    "c": "For downloading a video on Netflix",
    "d": "For streaming a podcast on Spotify",
    "feedback": "B, Games, Video Streaming, and Audio are generally resistant to packet loss and require real-time data, so re-transmission of packets and performance overhead of the handshake make these scenarios a better situation to use UDP."
},
{
    "question": "What is ICMP primarily used for ?",
    "dom": "network",
    "answer": "b",
    "a": "Exfiltrating data in a slow, but covert manner from an internal network.",
    "b": "To report errors and provide network information.",
    "c": "To ping whether a host is operational or not.",
    "d": "To test the latency of a request in an internal network.",
    "feedback": "B, ICMP can be used for data exfilrtration, to ping hosts, and to test latency and routing using tracert. But option B consolidates all of these into a single answer."
},
{
    "question": "You notice that the guidance for approved cryptographic algorithms has been changed since the last time you modified the internal documents. Where would be the appropriate place to update these changes? ",
    "dom": "grc",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "Policy, Standards, Procedures, Guidelines",
    "b": "Policy, Standards, and Procedures",
    "c": "Standards and Procedures",
    "d": "Policy Only",
    "feedback": "C, The overall policy is unlikely to have changed (Use strong encryption where necessary) so an update to the policy is overall unnecessary. The Standards state the details to exact the policy (Use this crypto algorithm with this key length), and will need to be updated. The Procedures provide Operations teams with exact instructions for how to implement the standard (Step 1. run this command). Guidelines can be largely ignored."
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following scenarios ensures Confidentiality AND Non-Repudiation from Alice?",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "c",
    "a": "Alice uses Bob's public key to encrypt data and then sends the data to him. Bob decrypts this data using his private key.",
    "b": "Alice uses her private key to encrypt data and then sends the data to Bob. Bob decrypts this data using Alices public key.",
    "c": "Alice uses her private key to encrypt the data. She then encrypts the data again using Bob's public key. She then sends the data to Bob. Bob decrypts the Data using his private key first, and then using Alice's public key.",
    "d": "Alice uses her public key to encrypt the data. She then encrypts the data again using Bob's public key. She then sends the data to Bob. Bob decrypts the Data using his private key first, and then using Alice's private key.",
    "feedback": "C. Encrypting using your private key and your recipients public key ensure that the message came from Alice as it would not decrypt without using her public key. If only Bob's public/private key pair is used, then there we cannot establish the message was from Alice. If we use Alice's public key for encryption, we would have a key-sharing issue with her private key and Bob. Similarly, if Alice ONLY encrypts using her private key, then anybody will be able to read her message using her public key."
},
{
    "question": "What is ICMP primarily used for ?",
    "dom": "network",
    "answer": "b",
    "a": "Exfiltrating data in a slow, but covert manner from an internal network.",
    "b": "To report errors and provide network information.",
    "c": "To ping whether a host is operational or not.",
    "d": "To test the latency of a request in an internal network.",
    "feedback": "B, ICMP can be used for A, C, and D. But B covers the broadest and highest level use cases for ICMP."
},
{
    "question": "When can MD5 be an appropriate hashing algorithm ?",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "b",
    "a": "When we need to protect the confidentiality of data like passwords.",
    "b": "When the confidentiality of the data is not relevant, but the integrity of it is.",
    "c": "When we need to protect both the confidentiality and integrity of data.",
    "d": "MD5 is an outdated hashing algorithm and has no current use-case.",
    "feedback": "B, while MD5 is an insecure algorithm, in contexts like data integrity checks it is still okay to use. The preferred option is SHA256, but that is not always available in legacy environments. Confidentiality is not protected by MD5 due to collissions and ease of compute. MD5 is outdated, but it is not true to say that it has no current use-case."
},
{
    "question": "Asking a colleague for access to their laptop is what potential form of attack ?",
    "dom": "basics",
    "answer": "a",
    "a": "Social Engineering.",
    "b": "Phishing.",
    "c": "Tailgating",
    "d": "Theft",
    "feedback": "A, Attacks that involve making people do something for you, usually in a veiled attempt to be nice or abuse human nature are considered social engineering attacks. A phishing attack establishes an entryway into an organisation using a lure (email, message, call, etc). Tailgating is following someone into a building through a gate. Theft is physical stealing of a device, not asking to use one. "
},
{
    "question": "In the context of AWS IAM, Which of these is NOT viewable ?",
    "dom": "cloud",
    "answer": "d",
    "a": "Access Key Expirations",
    "b": "Assigned Security Groups",
    "c": "MFA Status",
    "d": "Password Strength",
    "feedback": "D, Password Strength should not be auditable, as then it would indicate the passwords are stored in an insecure manner. MFA Status, Access Key Expiration Dates, and Assigned Security Groups are all part of the IAM Console."
},
{
    "question": "Which of these is NOT a challenge for traditional Static Analysis tools ?",
    "dom": "appsec",
    "answer": "d",
    "a": "High false positive reporting rate.",
    "b": "Challenges with language coverage and translation.",
    "c": "High computation time, especially on larger codebases.",
    "d": "Demonstrating the flow of tainted data from vulnerability source, to sink.",
    "feedback": "D, SAST tools usually implement an AST analyzer to help look for data source to sink, or at the least a GREP engine. High false positive rate, language coverage, and computational complexity are all challenges with operating a SAST tool."
}
]